【The fate that cannot be liberated】
【无法解脱的命运】
[Episode 15]
[第15集]
His brother sacrificed himself and left him with Rong Yu.
他的哥哥牺牲了自己 ，把他留给了容羽。
They want you to live a normal life.
他们希望你过上正常的生活。
if i were your family
如果我是你的家人
I don't want you to get involved again.
我不希望 你再卷入其中。
If you decide to refuse,
如果你决定拒绝，
I will understand.
我会理解的。
Indeed, I carry a heavy burden.
确实，我背负着重担。
my only burden is
我唯一的负担是
Why does Your Majesty trust you?
陛下为何信任
For an ordinary woman like me.
对于我这样一个普通的女人来说。
Because you are from the He family.
因为你是何家的人。
I checked
我查了一下
A letter condemning the He family
谴责何氏家族的一封信
It was forged by Mr. Zhongyong.
是仲永先生伪造的。
Those who will not betray Jialin
那些不会背叛家霖的人
It must be the He family.
肯定是何家。
Only Your Majesty
唯有陛下
do you know
你知道吗
Our loyalty.
我们的忠诚。
I will show you
我将向大家展示
one day.
一天。
I never gave up my desire to avenge my family.
我从未放弃为家人报仇的愿望。
His Majesty also said
陛下还说
I am from the He family.
我是何家的。
Since the death of my father and brother,
自从我的父亲和兄弟去世后，
Clean up the responsibilities of the loyal palace
清扫忠诚宫廷的责任
Protect the country and His Majesty
保护国家和陛下
fell on me.
落在我身上。
A deposed emperor.
一个被废黜的皇帝。
A female general.
一位女将军。
We are affected by our environment. The road ahead is difficult,
我们受到环境的影响。 前路艰辛，
I have no idea
我不知道
How far can we go together.
我们能一起走多远。
I go
我去
Do your best.
尽力而为。
I have nothing to give you
我没有什么可以给你的
But my father only left me a hundred secret guards.
但父亲只给我留下了一百名暗卫。
You can ship them however you want.
您可以随心所欲地运送它们。
Some hid in the palace,
有的躲进皇宫，
Others, outside it.
其他人，在它之外。
No one knows they exist.
没有人知道他们的存在。
- listen. - Yes.
- 听。 - 是的。
from now on,
今后，
The one next to me
我旁边的那个
will be your new owner.
将成为你的新主人。
her words
她的话
Those are my words.
是我的话。
- Understood. - Spread out to investigate.
- 明白了。 - 分散去调查。
Sim.
西姆。
It was you who killed your father
是你杀了你的父亲
and brothers.
和兄弟们。
We do not collude with the enemy.
我们不与敌人勾结。
I didn't collude with Xunnan either.
我也没有和寻南勾结。
And Xunnan?
和寻楠？
I know nothing about Xunnan.
我对寻南一无所知。
Instead of seeking revenge,
而不是寻求报复，
It would be better if you took your own life.
如果你结束自己的生命会更好。
You are the real culprit.
你才是真正的罪魁祸首。
It was you who caused death
是你造成了死亡
- from your whole family! - shut up.
- 来自你的全家！ - 住口。
Jiuling,
Jiuling,
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
What?
什么？
whenever i miss you
每当我想念你的时候
You show up.
你出现了。
That's legal.
那个合法的。
Sim.
西姆。
always
总是
It will appear when I am sad.
会在我难过的时候出现。
No.
不。
Not sad.
不悲伤。
I mean, I miss you.
我的意思是，我想你。
it's getting dark.
天快黑了。
Why are you here?
你为什么来这里？
I bought you some candies.
我给你买了一些糖果。
And you?
你呢？
Why are you here alone so late?
这么晚了你怎么一个人在这里？
I asked the young master to take me out of the palace to buy some.
我让少爷 带我出宫去买。
You like it.
你喜欢。
He learned to do things alone.
他学会了独自做事。
Why don't you send them to your house?
你为什么不把他们送到你家？
What if you get lost?
如果你迷路了怎么办？
How do I get home?
我该如何回家？
I won't get lost. I remember the way to the store
我不会迷路的。 我记得去商店的路
and the path to the astrology gallery.
以及通往占星馆的道路。
And how to pick you up at home.
以及到家接你的方式。
you know i don't
你知道我不
Did I pick you up at home?
我去家里接你了吗？
We go home.
我们回家吧。
Your Highness.
殿下。
We worked hard for several days and nights to get here.
我们辛苦了几天 几夜才到达这里。
He had been out for almost six hours.
他已经在外面呆了快六个小时了。
The wind is very cold.
风很冷。
Please take good care of yourself.
请好好照顾自己。
Let's find an inn.
我们找个客栈吧。
The books and pens are here.
书和笔都在这里。
Children's foldable turtle
儿童可折叠乌龟
I gave it to you last time
上次给你
Also here.
也在这里。
everything's ready.
一切准备就绪。
This is a festival.
这是一个节日。
Many shops outside are closed.
外面很多商店 都关门了。
Why go to an astrology studio?
为什么要去 占星馆上课？
This is not a class.
这不是一个班级。
Teachers gather together
老师们齐聚一堂
The homeless young disciples
无家可归的小弟子们
Study roles they have learned previously.
研究 他们之前学过的角色。
In fact,
事实上，
It’s up to the young master whether he goes or not.
去不去就看少爷了。
So, Rong Yu, we don’t want
所以，容宇，我们不要
Go to an astrology studio.
到占星馆。
last night,
昨夜，
The wind blew all night.
风吹了一整夜。
It's still cloudy now.
现在还是多云。
It may rain.
可能会下雨。
Master. you can barely remember
少爷。你几乎记不起
There is nothing in the class.
课堂上什么也没有。
We'd better stay home.
我们最好呆在家里。
No, we have to go.
不，我们得走了。
Master, you have changed. He doesn’t even take advice anymore.
少爷，你变了。 他甚至不再接受建议。
I want to work harder
我想更加努力
and learn more about things.
并更多地了解事物。
This way I can protect you in the future.
这样我才能在未来保护你。
Jiuling,
Jiuling,
Not only is it cold outside, it's also dangerous.
外面不仅寒冷， 而且还很危险。
Do you know this is dangerous?
你知道这很危险吗？
Today I will take you to an astrology center.
今天我带大家去占星馆。
let's go.
我们走吧。
- You can leave now. - Yes.
- 你现在可以离开了。 - 是的。
At.
于。
Are you going to an astrology clinic?
你要去占星馆吗？
Today is a school day.
今天是上学日。
Flatten, be careful , and stay closer to the young master.
展平，小心一点 ，离少爷近一些。
The capital is unstable.
首都不稳定。
and.
和。
Yu, you can go.
宇，你可以走了。
I want to talk to He Jiuling.
我要跟贺九菱谈谈。
Wait for me in the carriage.
在车厢里等我。
Today I will take you to an astrology center.
今天我就带大家 去占星馆。
you are now
你现在是
More convincing than me.
比我更有说服力。
I took care of him for many years.
我照顾他很多年了。
You flatter me.
你阿谀奉承我。
I was not flattered.
我并不受宠若惊。
Whether in the past or now,
无论过去还是现在，
Whether he understands it or not,
不管他明白与否，
he often
他经常
Be honest with you.
对你很诚实。
This is quite ironic.
这颇为讽刺。
my Lord.
我的主。
yesterday
昨天
When you leave the palace
当你离开皇宫后
He came back very late.
他很晚才回来。
where did you go?
你去哪儿？
Do you need me to say more?
还需要我说吗？
Do
做
- Is there anything you can't pronounce? - No.
- 有什么不能发音的吗？ - 不。
Since there is not,
既然没有，
Why should he return the carriage that was supposed to carry her?
他为何要归还本该载着她的马车，
And send the servants home?
并遣散仆人 回家？
He was alone.
只剩下他一个人了。
In this capital,
在这座首都，
Place and content
地点和内容
Can you let me stay late?
你能让我留到很晚吗？
I went to see my father.
我去看我的父亲。
Because, on Lunar New Year’s Eve,
因为，在农历除夕夜，
I'm home alone.
我一个人在家。
Better go visit my father
最好去拜访一下我的父亲
my brother and sister-in-law
我的哥哥和嫂子
And spend the holidays with them.
并与他们一起度过节日。
Are you exaggerating?
你夸张吗？
But you don't have to go alone.
但你不必一个人去。
I know you don't like my family
我知道你不喜欢我的家人
I don't want people in the house
我不想让房子里的人
Know where I'm going.
知道我要去哪里。
and how it should be
以及它应该如何
It's a night of reunion,
是一个团聚的夜晚，
Why do I want everyone to go to the cemetery with me ?
为什么要让大家 跟我一起去墓地
And take the bad luck home with you?
并把坏运气带回家？
So I sent them back.
于是我就让他们回去了。
If you think my words or actions are inappropriate,
如果您认为我的言行 不当，
There won't be a next time.
不会有下一次。
You can leave now.
你现在可以离开了。
Yu has been waiting for you for a long time.
宇已经等你很久了。
【Rongfu】
【荣府】
- It's cold? - No.
- 是冷的？ - 不。
This is very cool.
这非常酷。
Are you on the wagon now?
现在你已经上了马车了吗？
if you lie to me
如果你对我撒谎
I'm not talking to you anymore.
我不再和你说话了。
joke.
玩笑。
know the danger
知道危险
Who mentioned it before?
前面谁提到过？
Like if you fell into a lake.
就像你掉进湖里一样。
I don't know why he went to the water to catch fish last time.
我不知道他 上次为什么去水里抓鱼。
Who told you this nonsense?
谁告诉你这些废话的？
In the future, no matter what others say,
未来， 不管别人怎么说，
Don't listen.
别听。
you understood?
你明白了？
So tell me.
所以告诉我。
Who else?
还有谁？
Except Rong Ye,
除了荣爷之外，
o Zhanping,
o Zhanping,
a Heshan,
a Heshan,
Others are seen as others.
其他人被视为其他人。
And you?
你呢？
about me,
关于我，
You shouldn't listen to me either.
你也不应该听我的。
in fact
事实上
I'm a liar.
我是个骗子。
Like I'm lying now.
就像我现在撒谎一样。
Not the future,
不是未来，
I will tell you a lot of lies.
我会告诉你很多谎言。
You are different from others.
你和其他人不一样。
You don't look like
你不像
So does my uncle.
叔叔也是。
what is the difference?
有什么不同？
A
A
the difference
不同之处
This is
这是
you are mine.
你是我的。
Rong Yu, who did you learn this from?
容宇，你这是跟谁学的？
But did you learn it at the Astrology Pavilion?
但你是 在占星阁学过的吗？
Are you spying on others reading?
你在监视别人读书吗？
selenium
硒
Your facial expression may be a little more angry
你的面部表情可能 更生气一点
There is more evil
还有更多的邪恶
Probably not that funny.
可能没那么好笑。
I won't be angry with you.
我不会生你的气。
I won't be mean to you either.
我也不会对你刻薄。
I'm yours too.
我也是你的。
I'm yours.
我是你的。
So from now on I will only listen to you.
所以以后我就只听你的了。
Is he okay?
他还好吗？
Your Majesty, we have arrived.
陛下，我们已经到了。
Miledy.
米莱迪。
Milady, why are you blushing?
米莱迪，你的脸怎么红了？
It must be because the cabin is stuffy.
一定是因为车厢里很闷。
Was it very stuffy there at that time?
那个时候那里很闷吗？
My face was frozen.
我的脸都冻僵了。
So why don't you come in?
那么你为什么不进来呢？
I can go.
我可以走。
I can still walk a little.
我还可以走一点路。
Meet my friend Wu Ritan.
认识一下我的朋友吴日坛。
It's raining. It's raining.
下雨了。下雨了。
Quickly!
迅速地！
It's raining.
下雨了。
Zhangping
Zhanping
Zhanping!
Zhanping!
Master.
少爷。
It's raining.
下雨了。
Yes, Master, the lady said it's going to rain, and it's raining hard.
是啊，少爷，小姐说 要下雨，而且雨下得很大。
Could it be that after spending so long with the young master?
难道 和少爷相处了这么久，
Has she also learned to predict the future?
她是否也学会了预测未来？
- How can I. - Umbrella!
- 我怎么能。 - 伞！
I know, young boss.
我知道，年轻的老板。
When you finish writing the characters,
当你 写完人物的时候，
If it's still raining, I'll get an umbrella.
如果雨还在下，我就去拿伞。
Jiuling didn't bring an umbrella.
九龄没有带伞。
correct.
正确的。
You didn't take an umbrella with you when you left.
走的时候你也没有带伞。
- Fortunately, it didn't rain heavily. - I'll ask someone to bring it.
- 幸运的是，雨不大。 - 我会请人拿来的。
Master, wait for me.
少爷，等我一下。
I know
我知道
About what happened in Xunnan
关于寻南发生的事
You have no choice.
你别无选择。
Even if you want to save me
就算你想救我
Can't change the outcome.
无法改变结果。
Even though I'm a king now,
尽管我现在是国王，
and has a high status,
并且拥有很高的地位，
all
全部
You can't go back.
你不能回去。
This time I came to Jialin
这次我来到嘉林
To save his father and brothers.
为了拯救他的父亲和兄弟。
But I didn't expect that.
但我没想到。
Ling, the only thing I can do now is
凌，我现在唯一能做的就是
I just want to take you away.
就是要带你走。
Although?
虽然？
I can help you get revenge.
我可以帮你报仇。
I can give you anything you want.
我可以给你任何你想要的东西。
If you want to play freely in the bamboo forest,
如果你想在竹林里自由自在地玩耍，
random.
随意。
If you want to bully you again
如果你又想欺负你的话
In Xunnan, I will protect you,
在寻南，守护着你，
No one dares to hurt him again.
没有人敢再伤害他。
There is such a depressing place
还有这么压抑的地方
And such a marriage,
而这样的婚姻，
i don't want you
我不希望你
Continue for another day.
再持续一天。
Teacher Rong has done a lot for you.
容老师为你做了很多事。
I will find a way to cure him.
我会想办法治愈他的。
Will you follow me to Xunnan?
跟我去寻南好吗？
Why do you hesitate?
你为什么犹豫？
Miledy. it hurts. it hurts.
米莱迪。好痛。好痛。
looking at you. She is already an adult
看着你。她已经是一个成年人了
And just know how to play.
并且只知道怎么玩。
But isn’t it a holiday?
但这不是假期吗？
Why don't you leave me alone? stop complaining.
你为什么不留下我一个人？ 停止抱怨。
Are you annoyed by my complaints? I'm going to beat you.
你对我的抱怨感到恼怒吗？ 我要打败你。
This is a holiday.
这是一个假期。
I'm very happy. You're happy too, right?
我很开心。 你也很高兴，对吧？
When you see Yuhan, don’t tell her
等你见到雨涵的时候， 不要告诉她
It means you are not sleeping at home.
说明你没有在家睡觉。
She doesn't care. I do not care.
她不在乎。我不在乎。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
Yuhan told me she was fine.
雨涵告诉我她很好。
I didn't expect that she would have a lover now.
没想到她 现在竟然能有爱人了。
The man in dark clothes
那个穿着深色衣服的男人
This is definitely not Rong Yu.
这绝对不是容羽。
They just stood there talking.
他们只是站在那里说话。
How did he become a lover?
他怎么变成情人了？
Why don't you stay with me?
你为什么不留在我身边？
Let's take a look.
让我们来看看吧。
Why do you hesitate?
你为什么犹豫？
Don't go, sister.
别走，姐姐。
Silta. he.
斯尔塔。他。
No, it’s Mrs. Rong!
不，是容太太！
How strange to see you! My brother and I came over to say hello.
见到你真奇怪！ 我和弟弟过来打招呼。
Who is this?
这是谁？
you do not need to know.
你不需要知道。
how long.
多久。
You still here
你还在
This is very rude.
这是非常粗鲁的。
Not long ago, you experienced a great disaster.
不久前，你经历了一场大灾难。
But she doesn’t teach you how to be a human being.
但她没有教你如何做人。
You've crossed a line, sister.
你越界了，姐姐。
- You dare to hit me? - No.
- 你敢打我？ - 不。
It seems so.
看来是这样。
criminal's daughter
罪犯的女儿
He has not learned to be cautious and is arrogant.
他没有学会谨慎，而且很傲慢。
i need to know today
我今天需要知道
Who is this guy.
这个人是谁。
Who is so blind?
谁这么盲目？
- Jiuling, I bought you an umbrella. - Yu Rong,
- 九菱，我给你买了伞。 - 于蓉,
It's not raining now.
现在不下雨了。
correct.
正确的。
Master Rong.
荣师傅。
Master, when I parked the carriage,
少爷， 当我停好马车的时候，
I throw mud at you
我向你扔泥巴
with mud.
与泥。
what can we do?
我们可以做什么？
May I ask the owner of Xingxiang Pavilion?
请问 星象阁的主人
compensation?
赔偿？
Well, I'm not going to make it up to you.
好吧，我不会补偿你的。
you.
你。
One piece of clothing is no big deal.
一件衣服没什么大不了的。
But Mr. Rong, your wife will meet a man on the street.
但是容先生， 你的妻子会在街上遇到一个男人。
I think this is a big problem.
我认为这是一个大问题。
Why are you looking at me?
你为什么看着我？
You are a man.
你是一个男人。
What?
什么？
Your voice is too loud.
你的声音太大了。
Your voice is deep.
你的声音很深沉。
He is a real man.
他是一个真正的男人。
Sorry, I didn't recognize you.
抱歉，我没认出你。
Rong Yu, what are you talking about?
容宇，你在说什么？
And you, why are you laughing?
而你，为什么笑？
Do que chamou a Rong Yu?
Do que chamou a Rong Yu?
What?
什么？
A fact known to everyone in the capital
首都所有人都知道的事实
What can't be said?
什么不能说？
Fool.
笨蛋。
You married a stupid man.
你嫁给了一个愚蠢的男人。
-Jiu Ling. - I'm acting.
-九龄。 - 我在演戏。
Ling, stop fighting.
凌，别打了。
how long,
多久，
Multiple sclerosis. Jiang
多发性硬化症。蒋
Still so ineffective.
还是那么无效。
Do you dare to hurt me?
你敢伤害我吗？
She is hurt.
她受伤了。
It's best to see a doctor.
最好去看医生。
Quickly.
迅速地。
Why did you mess with her?
你为什么要惹她？
- I'll tell you something. -Ling,
- 我会告诉你一件事。 -凌,
Are you OK?
你好吗？
I'm fine. Don't worry.
我没事。不用担心。
Who are you?
你是谁？
he is
他是
My big brother.
我的大哥。
Don't you need to go back to Xingxiang Pavilion?
不需要回 星象阁吗？
And you?
你呢？
My brother and I need to talk.
我和我哥哥 需要谈谈。
I will wait for you.
我会等你。
today,
今天，
Don’t you need to go to the Astrology Pavilion to practice calligraphy?
不需要去 占星阁练字吗？
I asked for leave from the teacher.
我跟老师请了假。
Then I'll send her back first.
那我先送她回去吧。
I will go with you.
我和你一起去。
[Turn around in the tavern]
[酒馆转身]
Have you got a meal yet?
你吃了吗？
not yet.
还没有。
I'll bring you something to eat.
我给你带点吃的。
What do you want to eat?
你想吃什么？
You know I'm not picky.
你知道我并不挑剔。
I'll prepare something fresh for you.
我会为你准备一些新鲜的东西。
I haven't eaten yet.
我还没吃饭呢。
I haven't finished eating yet
我还没吃完
Is there gold thread ramen this morning?
今天早上有金线拉面吗？
Zhanping wants you to eat eggs, but you can't.
展平要你吃鸡蛋， 你却不能。
Why haven't you eaten yet?
你怎么还没吃饭？
I didn't have lunch.
我没有吃午饭。
what time is it?
现在是几奌？
Then everything is fine.
那么一切都很好。
What do you want to eat?
你想吃什么？
- I have no idea. - you do not know?
- 我不知道。 - 你不知道？
Rong Yu, are you really hungry?
容羽，你真的饿了吗？
correct. I believe I have desires.
正确的。我相信我有欲望。
I'm going to buy some snacks.
我去买点零食。
do you remember me?
你还记得我吗？
It seems he doesn't remember at all.
看来他根本就不记得了。
you are no longer
你不再是
The best young master in Jialin.
嘉林最好的少爷。
I have no idea
我不知道
What makes you who you are today.
是什么造就了今天的你。
Theoretically
理论上
You shouldn't be like this.
你不应该这样。
It seems that Ling and I both owe you one.
看来我和凌都欠你一个。
You helped her.
你帮助了她。
Saved her life.
救了她的命。
I thank
我感谢
Replace the wine with a cup of tea.
用一杯茶代替酒。
Whether we thank you or owe you,
不管我们是感谢你 还是欠你，
We can't use Ling's life to repay.
我们不能用凌的生命来偿还。
what do you want? supreme status,
你想要什么？至高无上的地位，
get rich
致富
Or something else?
或者其他什么？
I can even promise
我什至可以承诺
to cure it.
来治愈它。
Master, do you understand what I mean?
少爷，你明白我的意思吗？
If you don't understand, that's okay.
如果你不明白，也没关系。
No consent is required.
无需同意。
Who are you?
你是谁？
who I am?
我是谁？
If I need to say anything
如果我需要说的话
consider me
考虑我
Someone who will steal your wife.
会抢走你妻子的人。
let me see.
让我看看。
No.
不。
Rong Yu,
Rong Yu,
Why is water splashing everywhere?
为什么水溅得到处都是？
Why are your hands red?
你的手为什么是红的？
Burned?
烧伤了？
Boss, bring me a basin of ice water!
老板，来一盆冰水吧！
- It's coming. - Flatten!
- 它来了。 - 展平！
Zhanping, come here quickly.
展平，你快过来。
The tea is a little hot. everything will get better.
茶有点热。 一切都会好起来的。
It might be nothing to others.
对于其他人来说可能没什么。
His frail body may have been scarred.
他虚弱的身体 可能已经伤痕累累。
let me see.
让我看看。
Have you ever been in a war?
你打过仗吗？
Do you think we can fight?
你觉得我们可以打架吗？
Indeed, sometimes
确实，有时候
He has a bit of a temper, like a child.
他脾气有点暴躁， 像个孩子。
Ignore him.
别理他。
I don't plan to.
我不打算。
What's there?
那里有什么？
The young master was burned to death.
少爷被烧死了。
Big book.
大部头书。
First I cool it with ice water.
首先我会用 冰水将其冷却。
- Go back and apply cooling ointment. - correct.
- 返回并涂抹冷却的药膏。 - 正确的。
Zhan Ping, take the young master home.
展平，带少爷 回家吧。
No.
不。
If you don't go home and apply ointment
如果你不回家涂药膏
You will be unable to sleep at night because of the pain.
你会因为疼痛而晚上无法入睡。
If you go there, I'll go too.
如果你去那里，我也去。
I'll be back soon.
我很快回来。
So I will come back later as well.
所以我也会稍后回来。
Rong Yu, you said you would listen to me.
容羽，你说过你会听我的。
European Union...
欧洲联盟...
You don't know how to take care of yourself,
你不知道如何照顾自己，
I do not blame you. I ask you to come back and give me medicine,
我不怪你。 我请你回来给我药，
This is for your own good.
这是为了你好。
You don't listen either.
你也不听。
Zhan Ping, take the young master back.
展平，带少爷回去吧。
Master, let’s go back first.
少爷，我们先回去吧。
Look, the lady is already angry.
瞧，小姐已经生气了。
Come, Your Majesty.
来吧，陛下。
My lady will be back soon.
我的夫人很快就会回来。
- Even? - Clear.
- 乃至？ - 清除。
let's go.
我们走吧。
Do you really want to come back later?
你真的要稍后再回来吗？
You didn't lie, did you?
你没说谎吧？
I won't lie to you.
我不会对你撒谎。
But you said in the carriage
但你在车厢里说
You are a liar.
你是个骗子。
- I... - I'm waiting for you at home.
- 我... - 我在家等你。
I only listen to you.
我只听你的。
Can you stop lying?
你能不说谎吗？
he's good.
他很好。
Come on, Master.
来吧，少爷。
Master, let's go.
少爷，我们走吧。
let's go.
我们走吧。
Come on, Master.
来吧，少爷。
It is said that when Mr. Song was in trouble,
据说宋 老爷出事的时候，
Someone forced Master Song's sedan to stop.
有人强行让宋大人的轿子 停了下来。
But we don't know who.
但我们不知道是谁。
The drug that caused Mr. Song’s driver to fall into coma
导致宋爷司机昏迷的药物
From the imperial concubine.
来自皇妃。
Only used in the palace.
只在皇宫里使用。
This is not something ordinary people can achieve.
这不是一般人能达到的。
People who can get this medicine
可以获得这种药物的人
Must be someone from the court.
肯定是宫廷里的人。
Who has close ties to the royal family.
谁与皇室关系密切。
Revenge on New Year's Eve.
除夕夜报仇。
Who has a grudge against him?
谁与他有仇？
Who is the biggest suspect?
谁是最大嫌疑人？
The biggest suspect
最大嫌疑人
He must be an orphan from the He family.
肯定是何家的孤儿。
Now, Lord Rong
现在，荣爷
They even sent someone to notify me.
还派人通知我。
He Jiuling went to the cake shop
贺九龄去了蛋糕店
That night in the west of the city
当晚在城西
Go buy candy.
去买糖果。
They have witnesses and physical evidence.
他们有证人和物证。
The young master can also confirm this.
少爷也能证实这一点。
Although,
虽然，
if she leaves the palace
如果她离开宫殿
Go west and east of the city
向西又向城东走去
Kill the Song Lord
杀宋主
Then return to Rongfu
然后返回荣府
I don't think she had enough time.
我认为她没有足够的时间。
A girl from the He family
何家的姑娘
Can't cause problems.
不能引起问题。
Her whole family died.
她的全家都死了。
No one wants to help her.
没有人愿意帮助她。
- Let's go to the Ministry of Justice. - let's go.
- 我们去司法部吧。 - 我们走吧。
Father I...
父亲我...
group.
派。
Are you tired?
你很累吗？
Sim.
西姆。
This depends largely on you.
这很大程度上取决于你。
between me and him,
我和他之间，
It's like a knot that can't be untied.
就像是一个无法解开的结。
Pai County,
拜县，
my brothers
我的兄弟们
My sister-in-law died too.
我的嫂子也死了。
if it weren't for him
如果不是他
Maybe I can't handle it.
也许是我应付不了。
we must look forward
我们必须向前看
Because there is light on the road ahead.
因为前面的路有光。
But what if the road ahead
但如果未来的路怎么办
Is this a darker abyss?
这是一个更黑暗的深渊吗？
Do you still have the courage to move on?
你还有继续前行的勇气吗？
Because of Rong Yu.
因为容宇。
He's here.
他在这里。
need me.
需要我。
Believe me.
相信我。
it makes me feel
这让我感到
There is still light in life.
生活中仍然有光明。
elder brother,
哥哥，
You want me to go with you.
你要我和你一起去。
I can not.
我不能。
Is it because of him?
是因为他吗？
Sim.
西姆。
Not really.
并不是。
You said I could be like before
你说我可以像以前一样
and do whatever you want.
并做任何你想做的事。
But Wuhuashan’s sister
但五华山的妹妹
and the bullies in the capital
和首都的恶霸
You can't live the way you used to.
你不能像以前那样生活了。
I repay Rong Yu.
我报答容羽。
As for deep hatred,
至于深仇大恨，
I need revenge.
我需要报仇。
The He family was attacked and beheaded.
何家遭到袭击并被斩首。
I don't know who that is.
我不知道那是谁。
But if you want to stay here alone and take revenge
但如果你想独自留在这里 报仇
Do you think you can really do it?
你认为你真的能做到吗？
I am.
我是。
Really,
真的吗，
Now in Nanjiang,
现在在南江，
you have been known
你已经被认识了
General Zuo.
左将军。
but in my heart
但在我心里
You will always be my little sister
你永远是小妹妹
No one knows anything
谁什么都不知道
And protected by Master and me.
并受到师父和我的保护。
Who doesn’t want to be a little sister?
谁不想当小妹妹
No one knows anything
谁什么都不知道
And protected by the master and you?
并且受到主人和你的保护？
I have no expectations
我没有期待
one day
一天
I have to find another way out
我必须另谋出路
where i was born
我出生的地方
I was raised that way.
我是被抚养长大的。
I always thought
我一直以为
I will always be that person
我永远都是那个人
Ignorant little girl.
无知的小姑娘。
If you have already made a decision,
如果你已经做出了决定，
I respect her.
我尊重她。
If one day you are tired
如果有一天你累了
I will help you.
我会帮你。
Master Danrong
但荣师傅
is a noble master
是一位高贵的大师
Born with a silver spoon in his mouth.
含着金汤匙出生的。
he will never be the same again
他将不再一样
Just like you and me.
就像你和我一样。
he can only be
他只能成为
His weakness on the road to revenge.
他在复仇之路上的弱点。
I see.
我明白。
all good.
都好。
I will wait for good news in Xunnan.
我会在寻南等待好消息。
next time you miss me
下次你想我的时候
I'll go right away.
我马上就去。
leave you here alone
把你一个人留在这里
here.
这里。
before leaving,
离开之前，
I'll keep a very skilled maid
我会留下一个非常熟练的女仆
To protect you.
为了保护你。
I don't need anyone to protect me.
我不需要任何人来保护我。
Let me do this for you.
让我为你做这件事。
when you want to write to me
当你想写信给我时
Give it directly to her.
直接送给她。
It's safer than giving it to someone else.
比送给别人更安全。
correct.
正确的。
You asked me about amnesia fans
你问我失忆粉的事
When I was in Nanjiang.
我在南江的时候。
I'm under house arrest
我被软禁
I didn't get a chance to respond.
我没有机会回应。
The little bug you put in the medicine
你放进药里的小虫子
can be suppressed
可以抑制
Venom activity.
毒液的活性。
But he also slowly
但他也慢慢地
Damage to organs.
损害器官。
I'm trying to come up with a solution.
我试图想出一个解决办法。
I don't know if it will work.
我不知道它是否会起作用。
♫ It’s when the sun sets in the evening♫
♫ 就是黄昏夕阳西下的时候 ♫
♫I have traveled thousands of miles ♫
♫我行万里路 ♫
♫ Play the sitar under the moonlight ♫
♫ 月光下演奏西塔琴 ♫
♫ Drinks won’t let me forget ♫
♫ 饮料不会让我忘记 ♫
♫I write to you about my desire♫
♫我写给你的渴望♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫ There is no escape from fate ♫
♫ 无法逃脱命运♫
♫Looking back I see you waiting♫
♫回首我看到你在等待♫
♫Our lives are full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满 欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Desire crystallizes into shining stars♫
♫ 欲望结晶 成闪亮的星系♫
♫ You turn around silently and close the wedding book♫
♫ 你默默转身 ，合上结婚簿♫
♫Ask how many stars there are in the sky♫
♫问天上有多少颗星星♫
♫I write to you about my desire♫
♫我写给你的渴望♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫ There is no escape from fate ♫
♫ 无法逃脱命运♫
♫Looking back I see you waiting♫
♫回首我看到你在等待♫
♫Our lives are full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满 欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Desire crystallizes into shining stars♫
♫ 欲望结晶 成闪亮的星系♫
♫I play the sitar softly waiting for someone like you♫
♫我轻轻地弹奏西塔琴 等待像你这样的人♫
♫In the end you are my inevitable destiny♫
♫最终你 是我不可避免的命运♫